Guide to the Lawrence F. Evans Collection, 1978-1988 AIS.1988.17
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Periodicals, I.
  - Tradeswomen by Tradeswomen Magazine, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Trade Tax by Tradeswomen Inc., 1986 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Tranet, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Twin Cities Cultural Worker by Twin Cities Cultural Workers Association, 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - The Unifier by USWA International Rank & File Caucus, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Union Democracy Review by Association for Union Democracy, 1975, 1979-180, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Unionews Underground Cable by Telecommunications International Union, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - The Unionist by Local 644 National Council of Field Labor Locals, AFC-E, AFL-CIO, 1980-1981, 1984-1986 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Unitarian Universalist World by Unitarian Universalist Association, 1983-1986 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - United Labor Action, 1984-1986 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - United Mine Workers Journal by United Mine Workers of America, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Update Central America by Inter-Religious Task Force on Central America, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - USA by Association of Community Organizations for Reform Now, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Voice of Labor by Roanoke APWU's, 1982-1984 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Washington Crap Report by Editors Release Service, 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Washington Report by Editors Release Service, 1983-1987 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - The Waste Paper by Sierra Club Atlantic Chapter Radioactive Waste Campaign, 1981, 1983-1986 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - WAVES by Northwest Passage, 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - The Welfare Righter by Welfare Rights Organizations, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Win-No-Win by The Desolation Center, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Women Against Sexist Violence in Pornography and Media, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Workers Democracy, 1981-1986 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Workers Education Center Bulletin, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Workers Tribune by Bolshevik League of the US, 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Working Classics by Red Wheelbarrow Press, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - The Wree-View by Women for Radicala and Economic Equality, 1979-1981 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - The Writer Uniter by Organizing Committee for a National Writers Union, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - You Heard It Through the Grapevine by United Way of Allegheny County, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Fuse by Arton's Publishing Inc., 1980 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Monthly Review: An Independent Socialist Magazine by Monthly Review Inc., 1979-1982 (Box 9, Folder 21-22)
  - Mountain Review by Appalshop Inc., 1976-1981 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Sea Alliance News by S.E.A., 1979-1985 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - SHMATE by Steve Fankuchen, 1983, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Solidarity by UAW International, 1977-1986 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Steel Labor by United Steelworkers of America, 1978-1982 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - URPE Newsletter by URPE, National, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - 1397 Rank & File by USWA Local 1397, 1979-1981 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - NOW! by The New Artists' Workshop, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 36)
- Clippings and Correspondence, 1981-1985; II.
  This series contains newspaper clippings regarding the activities of United Steelworker locals in response to the deindustrialization of Pittsburgh during the 1980s. Also included are articles written by and about Larry Evans in response to the declining steel industry and other labor related topics, including his work with The Mill Hunk Herald and trip to Donetsk, Ukraine. Correspondence with United Steelworkers locals and the national union are also present. Newsletters and flyers announcing events by grassroots organizations are included.
  - Clippings, 1982-1985 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Anti-War and Anti-Draft Clippings (Box 10, Folder 2-4)
  - Clippings, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 5-7)
  - Clippings, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 8-10)
  - USW Local 1196 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Armco (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Bethlehem Steel (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - USW Duquesne (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Foreign Steel (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Fort Pitt castings (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Heppenstalls (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - US Steel Irvin (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Latrobe Steel Union (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Levinson Steel (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Linden Hall (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - McConway and Torler, USW (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Mesta (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - US Steel National Tube Works (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Neville Chemical (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Pittsburgh-des Moines Steel (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Rockwell International, USW (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Steelworkers Oldtime Foundation (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - USW Local 1010 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Steelworkers Voice (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - United Steelworkers of America (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Steelabor (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Steelworkers Fight Back (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Foreign Steel News (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Steelworkers United for Employment (SUE) (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Steel News Service (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Steel Industry (Box 10, Folder 37-38)
  - USW Edgar Thomson (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - USW Johnstown (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - USW Local 1397 Homestead (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - US Steel Clairton (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - US Steel (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - USW District 31 Women's Caucus (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Vesuvius Crucible Co. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - USW Williams & Co. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Women in Steel (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Articles by Larry Evans (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Flyers for Mill Hunk Events (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Articles regarding Larry Evans (Box 11, Folder 11-12)
  - Clippings regarding Deindustrialization (Box 11, Folder 13-18)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - US Steel News, 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Mon Valley Unemployed Committee, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - USW, National and District, 1981-1984 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - USW Locals (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Newsletters (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Event Flyers (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Information on Organizations (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Research (Box 11, Folder 27)
- Publications, III.
  This series includes several publications regarding labor issues, such as workplace health concerns and deindustrialization. Also present is research on labor relations in the Soviet Union prior to Evans' trip to Donetsk, Ukraine.
  - Dialogue: An Art Journal by Ohio Foundation on the Arts, Inc., 1984 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Air Contaminants-Permissible Exposure Limits by OSHA, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - What Every Representative Should Know About Health & Safety by USWA, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - International Political Science Abstracts by International Political Science Association, 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Shutdown by David Moberg, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Comparative Survey of Major Collective Bargaining Agreements by Industrial Union Department, AFL-CIO, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Potential Health Hazards of Video Display Terminals by National Institute of for Occupational Safety and Health, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Steelyard Blues: News Structures in Steel by North American Congress on Latin America, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Radical America by Alternative Education Project, Inc., 1981 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - American Man by The Coalition of Free Men, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Labor Research Review: Up Against the Open Shop by Midwest Center for Labor Research, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Japanese Style Industrial Relations & Trade Union Rights, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - The Changing Situation of Workers and Their Unions by AFL-CIO Committee on the Evolution of Work, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Injured on the Job: a Handbook for Massachusetts Workers, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - The Soviet Trade Unions: A Collection of Background Materials, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - When a Conflict Arises... How Labor Disputes are Settled in the USSR by Yefim Ghershanov, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Cancer and the Worker by The New York Academy of Sciences, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Labor Research Review by Midwest Center for Labor Research, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Fugitive Industry: The Economics and Politics of Deindustrialization by Richard B. McKenzie, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 46)
- Film, IV.
  This series includes many oral history interviews for Evans' Steel Valley Stories project, which sought to document working class life both inside and outside of the steel mills. Also present are segments for the television series "Our Own Show" and video of meetings addressing the plight of the steel industry and its workers.
  - Linwood Brosier Interview for Steel Valley Stories (Box 11, Cassette 1-5)
  - Carmen Cortazzo interview for Steel Valley Stories (Box 11, Cassette 6-8)
  - Pat Darrough interview for Steel Valley Stories (Box 11, Cassette 9-11)
  - Birdie Dunlap interview for Steel Valley Stories (Box 11, Cassette 12-14)
  - John and Betty Kaczka interview for Steel Valley Stories, 1987 (Box 11, Cassette 15-20)
  - Shirley Nusser interview for Steel Valley Stories (Box 11, Cassette 21-23)
  - Rob Robertson and Bill Thomas interview for Steel Valley Stories (Box 11, Cassette 24)
  - Sonny Robinson interview for Steel Valley Stories (Box 11, Cassette 25-28)
  - Irene and Booker Turner interview for Steel Valley Stories, 1987 (Box 11, Cassette 29-32)
  - Oliver West and Ben Butler interview for Steel Valley Stories (Box 11, Cassette 33-36)
  - Nick Coles, Writers Workshop, 1984 (Box 11, Cassette 37)
  - Peter Orsik, 1984 (Box 11, Cassette 38)
  - Dave Demarest and Joel Sabadasz Writers Workshop, 1984 (Box 11, Cassette 39)
  - Jim Daniels Writers Workshop, 1984 (Box 11, Cassette 40)
  - Examining the Problems of the Unemployed for "Our Own Show", 1986 (Box 11, Cassette 41)
  - Interviews with Allies of the Unemployed for "Our Own Show", 1987 (Box 11, Cassette 42)
  - Pro-Peace for "Our Own Show", 1986 (Box 11, Cassette 43)
  - Bill Patterson and the Great Peace March from "Our Own Show", 1986 (Box 11, Cassette 44)
  - Great Peace March I: Bombs Away Boogie, etc. for "Our Own Show", 1986 (Box 11, Cassette 45)
  - Great Peace March II for "Our Own Show", 1986 (Box 11, Cassette 46)
  - Ohio Great Peace Marchers for "Our Own Show", 1986 (Box 11, Cassette 47)
  - Great Peace March: Interviews with Pennsylvania Marchers for "Our Own Show", 1986 (Box 11, Cassette 48)
  - Steelworkers Speak Out for "Our Own Show", 1986 (Box 11, Cassette 49)
  - Michael Harrington with Tri-State Conference on Steel (Box 11, Cassette 50)
  - Michael Harrington at UE Local #610, Wilmerding, PA (Box 11, Cassette 51)
  - Michael Harrington at UE Local #10 and at Foodbank in McKeesport, PA (Box 11, Cassette 52)
  - Association for Union Democracy Meeting, 1982 (Box 11, Cassette 53-54)
  - Mill Hunk #1, 1985 (Box 11, Cassette 55)
  - Churches of the Mon Valley Speak Out and Victory for Nabisco Workers, 1983 (Box 11, Cassette 56)
  - Steelworkers Speak Out, 1983 (Box 11, Cassette 57-62)
  - Hearings Before Pittsburgh City Council (Box 11, Cassette 63)
  - Homestead 1980 Centennial Celebration: Ron Weisen and Community Leaders (Box 11, Cassette 64)
  - Labor Day, 1984 (Box 11, Cassette 65)
  - Unions Under Attack, 1984 (Box 11, Cassette 66)
  - Unitarian Church Conference on Labor, 1983-1984 (Box 11, Cassette 67-68)
  - "The Judge", 1984 (Box 11, Cassette 69)
  - "Union Jack Speaks Peace", 1983 (Box 11, Cassette 70)
  - Pittsburghers Speak Their Peace, 1982 (Box 11, Cassette 71)
  - Nicaraguan Perspectives, 1983 (Box 11, Cassette 72)
  - El Salvador Speaks, 1982 (Box 11, Cassette 73)
  - Mill Hunk Story Hour, 1985 (Box 11, Cassette 74)
  - Poland Today, 1984 (Box 11, Cassette 75)
  - Russian Round Table, 1984 (Box 11, Cassette 76)
  - A Disarming Russian, 1983 (Box 11, Cassette 77)
  - Steelworkers Speak Out with French Workers, 1984 (Box 11, Cassette 78)
  - French Steelworkers, 1984 (Box 11, Cassette 79)
  - Your Rights Under Reagan, 1983 (Box 11, Cassette 80)
  - Rights on Trial, 1984 (Box 11, Cassette 81)
  - John and Betty Kaczka interview for "Steel Valley Stories", 1988 (Box 11, Cassette 82-83)
  - Bob Hutson interview for "Steel Valley Stories" (Box 11, Cassette 84-85)
  - John and Betty Kaczka of Glassport, Bob Robertson and Bill Thomas of Duquesne, 1988 (Box 11, Cassette 86)
  - Michael Harrington: Visits Tri-State Conference on Steel (Box 11, Cassette 87)
  - Michael Harrington: visits Mon Valley UE Local Wilmerding (Box 11, Cassette 88)
  - Michael Harrington: visits Mon Valley UE Local Wilmerding with Jerry Starr (Box 11, Cassette 89)
  - "Our Own Show" Pilot, 1983 (Box 11, Cassette 90)
  - Mill Hunk Herald Magazine, "Just for Kicks", "Our Own Show" #3, 1982 (Box 11, Cassette 91)
  - Our Own Show "Volunteering on the Northside (Lutheran Services Society)", 1985 (Box 11, Cassette 92)
  - "Our Own Show '88", "Feminization of Power, Mill Hunk MTV, Soviet American Baseball", 1987 (Box 11, Cassette 93)
  - Our Own Show "Pro-Peace" (Box 11, Cassette 94)
  - Steel Valley Stories with Dale Hathaway, 1984 (Box 11, Cassette 95)
  - Steel Valley Stories with Rich Libschur, 1986 (Box 11, Cassette 96)
  - Steel Valley Stories with Sonny Robinson of East Liberty, 1988 (Box 11, Cassette 97)
  - Steel Valley Stories "Talkin' with the Turners" with Irene and Booker Turner of Lower Burrell, PA, 1988 (Box 11, Cassette 98)
  - Steel Valley Stories with Linwood Brosier of Beltzhoover, "See that Building Intro" and "Flash Dance", 1988 (Box 11, Cassette 99)
  - Steel Valley Stories #6 with Bob Hutson, 1989 (Box 11, Cassette 100-101)
  - Steel Valley Stories featuring Joe Hughes Part I, 1989 (Box 11, Cassette 102)
  - Steel Valley Stories with Pat Darrough of Aliquippa, 1989 (Box 11, Cassette 103)
  - Steel Valley Stories with David Bensam (Box 11, Cassette 104)
  - Mill Hunk Story Hour "Manny Fried's Reading" and Our Own Story "Just for Kicks", 1982 (Box 11, Cassette 105)
  - Northside Series "Reaganomics Caberet", 1982 (Box 11, Cassette 106)
  - Mill Hunk Series "Nicaraguan November", 1983 (Box 11, Cassette 107)
  - "Pat Dobler Poetry", 1984 (Box 11, Cassette 108)
  - "Syzygy", 1984 (Box 11, Cassette 109)
  - "Sports Psyche", 1984 (Box 11, Cassette 110)
  - "Blueprint for Volunteer Action Fair and Conference", 1984 (Box 11, Cassette 111)
  - "French Steelworkers Part I and II", 1984 (Box 11, Cassette 112)
  - "R.U. Forum", 1985 (Box 11, Cassette 113)
  - Mill Hunk Series "Steel City Stories Writing Workshop #2" with Pat Oresick, 1985 (Box 11, Cassette 114)
  - "Bas-o-Bol Boogie – Graffiti", Mary Robb Jackson "Bobby McGee", and Raisinettes "In His Kiss, Boyfriend's Back, and Jammin' on S.S." (Box 11, Cassette 115)
  - "Raisinettes at Baseball Boogie", 1988 (Box 11, Cassette 116)
  - "Inside Food Co-op" (Box 11, Cassette 117)